Sangwon Seo

(832) 839-3228 | ■ sangwon.seo@rice.edu | ★ sangwonseo.com
 in sangwon91 | ■ SangwonSeo_ | ★ Google Scholar

Research Objectives

My research centers on Human-Robot Collaboration, Human-Centered AI, and Human Behavior Modeling. During my PhD, I developed imitation learning algorithms that can learn more general agent policies from diverse human behaviors, and an AI-based coaching algorithm that improves human-human and human-robot teamwork.

Education

Rice University, Houston, TX

Aug 2019 – Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

• Thesis (Tentative): AI-Assisted Teamwork

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2013 – Feb 2015

M.S in Bioengineering

• Thesis: Performance Enhancement in Heart Rate Variability Analysis with Constrained Missing RR Interval Estimation

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2009 – Feb 2013

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Thesis: Multiplexing of Bead-Based Immunoassays using a BioMEMS

Research Experience

Human-Centered AI and Robotics Group, Rice University

Aug 2020 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhav Unhelkar)

- Proposed an automated task-time intervention system to improve teamwork during tasks
- Developed sample- and label-efficient imitation learning algorithms to learn a generative model of team behavior
- Developed a hierarchical imitation learning algorithm to learn the intentional behavior of experts from demonstrations
- Implemented multiple web-based teamwork simulators

Biomedical Signal and Information Lab, Seoul National University

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

M.S Student (Advisor: Prof. Kwang Suk Park)

- Developed signal processing algorithms for daily monitoring of physiological signals
- Developed autoregressive–moving-average-based interpolation methods to fill in missing RR-interval values to enhance heart rate variability analysis

Biophotonics and Nano Engineering Lab, Seoul National University

Dec 2011 - Jun 2012

Research Intern (Advisor: Prof. Sunghoon Kwon)

Designed and implemented biomedical microelectromechanical systems (Bio-MEMS)

Industry Experience

Honda Research Institute USA, San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Research Intern

- Human behavior modeling and optimization for human-aware automation
- Developed mathematical models to capture changes in human propensities for interacting with other agents and learned these models from demonstrations.
- Inferred individual interaction propensities with other agents from observable states and actions using sequential Monte Carlo methods

Coreline Soft, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2016 – Jun 2019

Associate Research Engineer

- Responsible for developing algorithms for AVIEW MODELER, a medical 3D printing solution
- Developed geometric modeling and processing algorithms
- Implemented a volume and surface rendering pipeline

Agency for Defense Development, Daejeon, South Korea Researcher

Mar 2015 – Mar 2016

- Developed a telemetry system for aircraft
- * My employment at the Agency for Defense Development and Coreline Soft is recognized as fulfilling the compulsory military service in South Korea.

Publications

Full Papers

- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "IDIL: Imitation Learning of Intent-Driven Expert Behavior", 23nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2024 (Acceptance rate 25%)
- **S. Seo**, B. Han and V. V. Unhelkar, "Automated Task-Time Interventions to Improve Teamwork using Imitation Learning", *22nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS)*, 2023 (Acceptance rate 23.3%)
- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Semi-Supervised Imitation Learning of Team Policies from Suboptimal Demonstrations", *31st International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2022 (Acceptance rate 14.9%)
- **S. Seo**, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, M. A. Zenati, J. A. Shah, R. D. Dias and V. V. Unhelkar, "Towards an AI coach to infer team mental model alignment in healthcare", *2021 IEEE Conference on Cognitive and Computational Aspects of Situation Management (CogSIMA)*, pp. 39-44, 2021
- S. Kwon, D. Lee, J. Kim, Y. Lee, S. Kang, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Sinabro: A smartphone-integrated opportunistic electrocardiogram monitoring system", *Sensors*, 16(3), p.361, 2016
- S. H. Hwang, **S. Seo**, H. N. Yoon, H. J. Baek, J. Cho, J. W. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D.-U. Jeong and K. Park, "Sleep period time estimation based on electrodermal activity", *IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics (J-BHI)*, 21(1), pp.115-122, 2015
- S. Kang, S. Kwon, C. Yoo, **S. Seo**, K. Park, J. Song and Y. Lee, "Sinabro: Opportunistic and unobtrusive mobile electrocardiogram monitoring system", *15th Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile)*, pp. 1-6, 2014

Short Papers

- S. Seo, "AI-Assisted Human Teamwork", AAAI-24 Doctoral Consortium, 2024
- M. Khalid, S. Seo, M. A. Zenati, M. Ebnali, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, R. D. Dias, V. V. Unhelkar and E. Salas, "Opportunities and Challenges of Real-Time Measurement of Team Performance on the Cardiac Operating Room", Human Factors and Ergonomics Society (HFES) 67th International Annual Meeting, 2023
- J. Kim, S. Kwon, S. Seo and K. Park, "Highly wearable galvanic skin response sensor using flexible and conductive polymer foam", 36th annual international conference of the IEEE engineering in medicine and biology society (EMBC), pp. 6631-6634, 2014

Working / Under-review Papers

• **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Imitation Learning of Diverse Team Behaviors from Heterogeneous Demonstrations"

- **S. Seo**, B. Han, R. E. Harari, R. D. Dias, E. Salas and V. V. Unhelkar, "Improving Human Teamwork through Task-Time AI Assistance"
- S. Seo, S. Mehrotra, V. V. Unhelkar and K. Akash, CONFIDENTIAL

Honors & Awards

National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation

Mar 2009

Teaching Experience _____

Teaching Assistant

COMP 646: Deep Learning for Vision and Language (Prof. Vicente Ordóñez-Román) Spring 2023 COMP 440/557: Artificial Intelligence (Prof. Devika Subramanian) Fall 2021

Advising & Mentoring

Arnav Adhikari, Highschool Student, Houston, TX **Bing (Tim) Han**, Undergraduate Student, Rice University **Zhanyi Sun**, Undergraduate Student, Rice University

May 2023 – Dec 2023 May 2022 – May 2024 Jan 2022 – Jun 2022

Reviewer

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts (ARSO) Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Python | C | C++ | Javascript | HTML | SQL | Matlab | LaTeX

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES OpenGL | OpenMP | Flask | Gym | PyTorch | Tensorflow | WandB

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Git | Docker | CMake | VSCode | Jupyter

ROBOT DEVELOPMENT Motion Capture (OptiTrack) | ROS | MoveIt | OMPL

LANGUAGES English | Korean

Extra

AAMAS Student Volunteer

Student Venture Network, Seoul National University

College of Engineering Tennis Club, Seoul National University

Mar 2012 – July 2012

Mar 2010 – Feb 2013

System Administrator, ECE Department, Seoul National University

Mar 2010 – Feb 2011

SNU Mentoring, Seoul National University

Sep 2009 – Feb 2010